const readLineSync = require('readline-sync');

console.log('Welcome to the Javascript Quiz Wizard!!!! \n');
console.log('You will get 1 point for each correct answer and -1 for each wrong answer. At the end of the Quiz, your total score will be displayed. Maximum score is 10 points\n');

const name = readLineSync.question( 'Alright!!! Lets begin with the quiz. What is your name?\n');

console.log(`Hiii: ${name}. Good Luck !!!\n`);

const questions = [
  {
    question: "Who invented JavaScript?",
		answers: {
      a: "Douglas Crockford",
      b: "Sheryl Sandberg",
      c: "Brendan Eich",
      d:"Steve Jobs"
      },
		correctAnswer: '3'
  },
  {
    question: "Which tool can you use to ensure code quality?",
    answers:{
      a: "Angular",
      b: "jQuery",
      c: "RequireJS",
      d: "ESLint"
    },
    correctAnswer: '4'
  },
  {
    question: "JavaScript is a ___ -side programming language",
    answers:{
      a:"Client",
      b:"Server",
      c:"Both",
      d:"None"
    },
    correctAnswer:'3'
  },
  {
    question :"Which are the correct if statements to execute certain code if x is equal to 2?",
    answers:{
      a:"if(x%2)",
      b:"if(x==2)",
      c:"if(x!=2)",
      d:"if(x=2)"

    },
    correctAnswer:"2"
  },
  {
    question:"Which JavaScript label catches all the values, except for the ones specified?",
    answers:{
      a:"try",
      b:"catch",
      c:"label",
      d:"default"
    },
    correctAnswer:"4"

  },{
    question:"If the value of x is 40, then what is the output of the program? (x%10==0)?console.log(Divisible by 10): console.log(Not divisible by 10) ",
    answers:{
      a:"ReferenceError",
      b:"Divisible by 10",
      c:"Not divisible by 10",
      d:"None of the above",
    },
    correctAnswer:"2"
  },
  {
    question:"What Boolean(3<7) will return ?",
    answers:{
      a:"True",
      b:"False",
      c:"NaN",
      d:"None of the above"
    },
    correctAnswer:"1"
  },
  {
    question:"Determine the result -String('Hello') === 'Hello';",
    answers:{
      a:"True",
      b:"False",
      c:"SyntaxError",
      d:"ReferenceError"
    },
    correctAnswer:"1"

  },{
    question:"What is the correct JavaScript syntax to print “DataFlair” in the console?",
    answers:{
      a:"print(“DataFlair”);",
      b:"console.print(“DataFlair”);",
      c:"log.console(“DataFlair”);",
      d:"console.log(“DataFlair”);"
    },
    correctAnswer:"4"
  },{
    question:"Which of the given options is an incorrect variable name?",
    answers:{
      a:"javascript",
      b:"_javascript",
      c:"$javascript",
      d:"-javascript"
    },
    correctAnswer:"4"
  }

  ];
function displayQuestions(i){
  console.log(`Question${i+1} : ${questions[i].question} \n`);

}

/*function for displaying Options*/

function displayOptions(i){

  let optionArr =[];
    
    optionArr.push(questions[i].answers.a);
    optionArr.push(questions[i].answers.b);
    optionArr.push(questions[i].answers.c);
    optionArr.push(questions[i].answers.d+"\n");
    let optionNum =1;
    for(element of optionArr){
      console.log(optionNum+":"+" " + element);
      optionNum+=1;
    }

}

/*function for validation User Input*/

function validateInput(userInput){
  if(userInput>0 && userInput<5)
  return true;
  else
  return false;
}
/*Variable to hold the score of User*/

let score =0;

/*function to begin with Quiz*/

function startQuiz(questions){  

  for(let i =0;i<questions.length;i++){
    
    displayQuestions(i);
    displayOptions(i);

   const selectedOption = readLineSync.question('Please enter your option\n');

   if(validateInput(selectedOption)){

      if(questions[i].correctAnswer == selectedOption){
      console.log("Hurray !!!! CorrectAnswer\n");
      score++;
    }else{
      console.log("Oooops WrongAnswer\n");
      console.log(`Correct Answers is ${questions[i].correctAnswer}\n`);
      score--;
    }
    console.log(`Your current score is :${score}\n`);
    console.log("\n");
   }else{
     console.log("Invalid Input\n");
   }

   

  }

   return score;



}

function startGame(){

  let userScore = startQuiz(questions);
  console.log(`Thanks for your time, your total score is : ${userScore} out of ${questions.length}\n`);


}

startGame();




